注：Secret Informant意思是秘密线人，但是内容都是美食
Having never been to Hong Kong
第一次来香港
And not being able to read Cantonese
再加上对广东话一窍不通
注：中文字幕和英文字幕都是官方字幕
I could never really be sure during our trip about what kind of restaurant we are about to enter.
让我没有办法在进入餐馆前看出这家是什么餐馆
注：旁白是techlinked的Riley，本视频上传于20180914
Was it the equivalent of a local sandwich shop,
这究竟会是本地的快餐店呢
a late-night snack spot, or a family diner?
是一家吃夜宵的餐厅呢 还是一个家庭聚餐的小店
Turns out, Tak Fung noodles restaurant is the later.
最后发现 德丰粉面餐厅是后者
Owner Bryan Chung started it with help from his family,
老板Bryan在家人的协助下开了这家餐厅
And together they run it as a local place for individuals or groups to come and eat together.
他们一家齐心努力下 德丰餐厅广受本地食客喜爱
Tak Fung has a mix of traditional Chinese and western dishes,
德丰餐厅有一些中式和西式结合的菜肴
reflecting the dual identities of Hong Kong.
充分地体现出了香港中西结合的现状
There's even a 40 year old sauce,
店里最古老的酱汁已经有40年的历史了
But I'll let Bryan and our Tattler for this episode - Stanley, tell us more about that.
让Bryan老板和我们这一集的嘉宾Stanley来给我们介绍一下吧
首先让我来介绍一下这道鹅肉
这鹅肉没有40年这么久
我要说的是这做鹅肉的盐水酱
这盐水酱是在40年以前
餐厅刚开业的时候就开始制作了
在一批鹅肉煮完后这盐水酱不会丢掉
而是会加入新的一批盐水酱接着煮
这样一来时间久了这盐水酱就很有味
这酱料不会太咸而且会有岁月的香味
另外一道菜叫做啫啫滑鸡煲
这道菜在香港很多见
不过要做的好不容易
所以这个名字啫啫滑鸡煲
啫啫是当鸡肉放到热锅里时候的音效声是么
对啦没错没错 是因为这个声音才取这个名字的
好 最后我们来说说这道蚝仔饼
好的 这道蚝仔饼我们是加入鸭蛋制作的
只加鸭蛋的话会让饼的口感脆爽
你好像一个大厨哦
没啦 我很少煮菜的啦
不过我有时候会看看师傅怎么做菜的
所以 让大家尝尝我们餐厅的小菜
如果喜欢 多多光临
好的 一定 多谢你 Bryan
Oh, here it comes.
噢 来了来了
What is this?
这是什么内
This is the sizzling chicken pot.
这道叫做啫啫滑鸡煲
It is basically a very common dish among these local restaurants.
这是在香港本地餐厅里常见的一道家常菜
But to do it well it takes experience and skills from the chef.
不过做的好吃不好吃就要看师傅的经验和技术了
I feel like when you see like somebody who's like done this dish.
我觉得当你看到这道菜的时候就能感觉得出来
Like over and over...like they know it.
厨师反复不断地做同一道菜到了出神入化的地步
It's an art form.
这就是艺术
Yeah, cooking is an art form.
没错 煮菜就是一门艺术
Not just the sequence of steps you do but the way that you performed it.
不仅仅是按部就班地制作 而是要看每一步怎么做
Okay, what are we looking at here?
好了 这道是什么菜呢
What's this one? This is obviously a little bit more deep fried.
这道菜看得出来是油炸的
Yeah, this is the oyster omelette.
这道菜是潮州蚝仔饼
Oyster omelette?
蚝仔饼
Yeah, they use...actually use duck eggs instead of chicken eggs.
没错 他们用鸭蛋代替鸡蛋
They are seasoned eggs.
制作前有对鸭蛋进行调味
The little oysters are actually freshly caught everyday.
里面的小生蚝都是每天新鲜捕捉上来的
Wow, really. It looked like it was like a collection of a lot of small ones.
看得出来这是很多小生蚝团在一起
And then just placed very closely together so that they could form.
团在一起就变成了一大块
And I guess the egg is acting as like a sorta holder for them to stay together.
我猜这鸭蛋起到的就是把他们黏连在一起的作用
And the whole thing is deep fried.
然后整个放下去油炸
This dish looks relatively plain comparing to the other two.
这道菜和其他两道比起来相对的就比较简单
This was the one that Bryan highlighted the most.
这是刚才Bryan重点推荐的那道菜
So they actually braise the goose in a sauce that's been in the making for 40 years.
这道鹅肉的卤汁有40年的历史
The process of aging and updating that sauce for years and years
这种年复一年反复加入新汤汁熬制
That's like a traditional thing to do?
是一种很传统的做法么
That is, that is. Yeah.
没错没错
So like multiple restaurants will do it,
是不是很多餐厅都有这样做
They just have their own flavours.
他们各自都有自己独特的风味
Interesting. Wow. I mean that's really wow.
有趣 确实有趣
What is...uh...I don't even know what braising means.
我都不确定braising是什么意思
What does "braise" mean?
braise是什么意思
To cook in liquid, I believe.
我觉得是在汤汁中烧煮的意思
Yes, correct.
对 没错
Oh so, it's like boiling but in a sauce.
所以就是像煮开水 不过是在煮汤汁
Shall we? Which one are we doing first?
我们开始吧 先来尝哪一道呢
Omelette. Omelette? Because it cools off the fastest.
蚝仔饼么 嗯 因为它很快就凉了
Shall we? Alright gentlemen. Omelette's up. Oyster omelette.
我们开动吧 潮州蚝仔饼
It is not like the ordinary omelette.
这一点不像普通的鸡蛋饼吼
No.
完全不像
I took a bite thinking like, oh I'm gonna get egg, I'm gonna get oyster, and I'm gonna get the crispy outta shell.
我咬一口 想着会吃到蛋 会吃到生蚝 会吃到外面的脆壳
I got that crispy outta shell,
我吃到了脆脆的外壳
But I couldn't make the distinction between the egg and the oyster.
但是我没能够吃出里面蛋和生蚝的区别
Because they are kind of similar in texture as well.
因为它们的口感蛮接近的
It looks very crispy when you look at it,
这蚝仔饼看上去炸的很脆
But...as you can see...when you are getting in there with you chopsticks, it just kinda...kinda gives away.
不过用筷子夹的时候很容易就戳下去了
Like tofu. Yeah.
是啊 就像夹豆腐一样
Crispy chicken x2
脆脆鸡 x2
Is that what it's called?
是这么叫么
Sizzling chicken x3
啫啫滑鸡煲 x3
Dig in.
开吃
This is just like a solid, lightly fried,
这就像是一块肉厚的 稍稍油炸过
Piece of tender, juicy chicken.
肉嫩多汁的鸡块
Come on down, get your fried juicy chicken.
快来吃美味多汁的炸鸡
Now this is something that I can say is less intimidating
这道菜给我感觉比较容易让人接受
If you are unfamiliar with Hong Kong Cuisine,
如果你对香港的菜色不熟悉
Maybe you are too adventurous.
或者是你不是太敢于冒险
You are just like...give me some of that.
你就可以来试试看这个
It's like sweet and salty
就像是又甜又咸
I was gonna say 'sweet and sour',
我本来想说又酸又甜
But now 'sweet and salty'.
现在是又甜又咸
That's a good way to put it.
这个形容挺准确的
The grand finale.
上主菜咯
I've never had goose before.
我从来没吃过鹅肉
It's similar to duck, I would say.
鹅肉和鸭肉很像
I think we ought to start off with the dipping.
我觉得第一口就应该蘸酱料
You wanna start with the dip?
你一开始就要蘸酱哦
Then you are gonna double dip, and you are gonna eat it with the germs.
如果你先咬一口再蘸的话酱汁里就有细菌了
They have been preping this sauce for 40 years.
这蘸酱已经煮了40年了
And you wanna start with the dips?
然后你上来就吃精华哦
Is this a one biter?
这是一口吃的么
Depends, it's up to you.
取决于你想不想一口吃咯
It looks like you are ready to eat it in one bite.
你看起来准备好一口了
Yeah, I am doing it one-bite.
嗯 我准备一口
It is like...
这个口感
...so moist,
非常湿润
and so...
而且又
...full of juice...and sauce.
非常多汁多酱
You have been forgiven for thinking it was dark meat.
你已经不会觉得这个是红肉了
Well, that's the whole point of braising, right?
卤肉就是这个目的
Salty.
很咸
There is a little bit...you can see like a little bit oil on top, but it's not oily.
表面有一些油却不是很油腻
It was very smooth. It wasn't overpowering.
口感顺滑而没有喧宾夺主
It was just...very flavourful and packed full of my tongue.
总之就是缠绕在舌尖的美味
You wanted to say 'rich' though, don't you?
你是不是想说浓郁
Yeah, 'rich' was like the automatic word in my head, but...
是啊 一开始想说浓郁的
You want to say 'rich' because it's a very good descriptive word.
你想说浓郁是因为这是一个很到位的形容词
I guess we are gonna end this up with a...signature milk tea.
在结束前我们来尝尝店里的特色奶茶吧
Hot milk tea x2
热奶茶 x2
Gentlemen, George. Thank you for bring us here.
George先生 感谢你带我们来到这里
George?
谁是George
Stanley x4
This is wonderful.
这很棒
Thank you for introducing us.
感谢你给我们做的介绍
And uh...let's have a clink...to end it off.
我们碰杯之后就结束吧
To good food.
为了好吃的食物
To delicious food and sauce for the ages.
为好吃的食物和40年的酱料
Thanks for watching this video which is produced by Tattle.
感谢您观看这集由 Tattle 制作的影片
You don't know, Tattle is a platform connecting savvy locals with curious explorers.
Tattle 是一个全新的帮助探险者连接本地向导的网络平台
Check us out on social media
来我们的社交媒体频道上看看
And sign up for the newsletter at the link in the description.
点击下面的链接订阅 Tattle 的每周电子期刊
Big thanks to Tak Fung noodles restaurant for having us,
非常感谢德丰粉面餐厅协助我们这一集的拍摄
And thanks to Stanley again for being our Tattler for this episode.
也再一次感谢 Stanley 作为这一集的嘉宾
Make sure to subscribe to Tattle for more videos from Secret Informant.
记得订阅我们的频道看更多精彩视频哟